Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
What point is there, in clinging to this planet?
We'll be entering the atmosphere shortly. Please return inside.
My secret police have already found all
subversive elements allied with Zoellick.
We'll be able to wipe them out before long.
I'm sorry for what I put you through.
Not at all, sir.
But now your rule is secure.
Despite the fact that I left the main fleet ninety days away?
Oh! Well...
I'm told they will take a minimum of three months to return to the Home Planet?
Balun is the center of the Geschtam Gates,
comprising the hyperspace navigation network.
Its destruction means that most of the primary fleets remain here.
In other words, it is now impossible
for our primary fleets to reach the Yamato via normal Geschtam navigation.
My lord...
Issue the order...
...to sink the Yamato.
Would you do it?
At the cost of my life.
We've prepared the best crew for you.
Should you defeat the Yamato,
your wife's punishment will be reduced.
I am grateful, Deputy Lord Hyss.
Elk, I have one more request...
Just for you.
You left the medical room. Makoto was looking for you.
So that's where you take off from, huh?
Well? Did you come to retrieve me?
Something like that.
Shinohara, you were in my brother Akio's squad, weren't you?
Yeah, he was a good man.
Sword 3 was his code name.
I see...
He never discussed that stuff.
That's the kind of guy he was.
We've made it to the Large Magellanic Cloud, haven't we?
Yes, we have.
Congratulations.
You were right. I never expected we'd ever get this far.
I don't know if "right" is the way I'd put it.
But there is only one reality.
And the reality is that we made it.
What are you looking at?
The stars.
The Tarantula Nebula? Impressive, isn't it?
Beyond it lies Iscandar.
I wanted to come home with Sasha.
Yurisha...
That's dangerous.
I'm sorry, Hoshina.
Yuria says she wants you to hug her.
What is a hug?
An Iscandarian on board the Yamato?
Unbelievable.
Remember when Cerestella went to Balun?
She was investigating the Aquarius ruins, yes?
She used the ruins to retrieve information on the Yamato.
I didn't know that was even possible!
She is a witch, after all.
And so, I have another mission now.
We're landing. Prepare to disembark!
Nothing but children and old men, huh?
"The best crew," right?
Only four carriers?
No complaints, Berger.
The Imperial Guard controls the Homeland Defense Fleets.
They won't give us more.
Barlen!
Heydeln, is that you?
I didn't think you were still alive!
Same to you!
It's been since the Gorni Campaign.
Indeed.
We have old ships and young men. Can you do this?
You were the one who said that a soldier comes of age on the battlefield.
I'm counting on you.
Zar Belk!
Attention!
Flakken, I'll need your help once more.
The air in Baleras is horrible.
I'd jump at the chance.
I'm counting on you.
A squad of second-class Garmillas subjects?
Volunteers from Planet Zaltz.
From a conquered territory?
They're from the same planet as Schultz.
We are the 442nd Special Platoon, Specialized Warfare Group B.
I have an extremely important mission for you. You're aware of it, correct?
We will do all we can for Garmillas.
I'm not sure we can trust them.
Our noble home,
Planet where the blue flowers blossom.
Sing a song of joy!
May god's grace always be with us.
Ghale Garmillon!
Hail to the victory of our home.
Regular Wave Motion Gun inspection is complete.
All responsible personnel should report to Weapons Officer.
Keep this thing in good shape.
No matter how often the Garmillans show up,
the Yamato is invincible so long as we have this.
Oh!
Captain...
Do you need something?
No, it's nothing.
What's wrong with him?
No idea...
What lies back there is a tool of war.
Wave Motion Energy is not a weapon.
You mustn't make it a weapon.
It is to enable you to cross the stars.
The plans you received a year ago were to take you to Iscandar.
During our journey of 168,000 light years, we required protection from Garmillas.
And therefore, Sanada created it.
Crime and Punishment
But that makes you no different than the Garmillans
Is the wave motion gun truly only for your protection?
I'd like for you to believe in us.
Why...
Why not ask me?
Why we didn't bring you
the Cosmo Reverser directly,
rather than the Wave Motion Engine?
Perhaps we are being tested.
By you... By your people.
I simply observe.
It is my sister, Starsha's job to decide.
Then I hope you'll watch carefully.
And see if the Yamato...
No, whether humanity is worth saving.
Once the weapons are aboard the Domelaze
7th Maintenance Company is to begin loading fighters onto the Balgrey.
A top-secret prototype... No less.
It wasn't easy convincing Weapons Research.
I'm grateful.
It's fine... I'm accustomed to your requests.
But why would you need such a thing?
Isn't this a drill for asteroid mining? Why load it as a bomb?
Who knows? I'll never understand the higher-ups.
Lieutenant Brigadier!
What are you doing with him?!
Stay calm.
I've done nothing to make them arrest me. They'll see that when they investigate.
Lieutenant Brigadier Helder!
Damn you!
This is what's really happening in the home we're risking our lives to protect.
Who are you guys?
Lower Storm Leader Melda Ditz, right?
The Tarantula Nebula, at the edge of the Large Magellanic Cloud,
is filled with interstellar medium and ion storms.
These seven stars make up the nebula.
For convenience, we'll call them the Rainbow Cluster.
Heading through this is our fastest course.
But degenerate stars comprise this cluster, and it's also filled with relativistic jets.
It is the most dangerous area along our course.
We're already seeing issues with the Cosmo Radar.
Can't we just warp through?
Even at maximum warp, we wouldn't make it through. It's too big.
It'll be difficult to get through.
Yes, so I've charted a course around it.
This is the course we believe the Yamato will take on their way to Salezar.
Then the quickest route is through the Rainbow Cluster?
Heading through that would be suicide. They aren't that stupid.
If they plan to avoid the Rainbow Cluster, that doesn't leave many routes.
No...
Even if we did gain a step on them at Balun,
navigating around would give the enemy time to mount a counterattack.
The enemy is also unlikely to expect us to go through a dangerous area like this.
Yes, we will continue through the Rainbow Cluster, to Iscandar.
As we travel through the cluster, we will maintain alert status
and carefully monitor anti-air scanners.
09 - minutes
Balgrey ready to launch.
Lambea ready to launch.
Schderg ready to launch.
Daurold ready to launch.
All ships ready to launch.
Launch all ships.
The fleet is passing Second Baleras.
I will now announce our course.
Course 728. Our destination is the Rainbow Cluster.
The Rainbow Cluster?
Seriously?
But will they really come through such a dangerous area?
They will come.
If the captain of the Yamato is the man I think him to be,
they will come through the Rainbow Cluster.
High-density ionized gas!
S-Switching helm to manual!
Radar and sensors aren't working correctly.
Switching to optic mode.
So we'll have to rely on optic mode?
We're like an old sailing ship.
If the enemy is the commander we faced before...
There's a storm up there, Heyni.
Sounds good!
Ship detected at nine o'clock.
There it is.
Message from the Hound! The sheep has entered the lost forest.
You were right.
Yes.
We will commence the operation.
Fighter Group 1, prepare for launch.
Attention all decks: First Attack Force, prepare for launch.
Captain...
I'll count on you for the rest.
Good luck, Rear Brigadier.
70 gek to the operation area.
Will they attack in rough seas like these?
Shino isn't with us this time.
Don't be so scared, Kobashi.
I'm not scared!
Don't worry.
If anything happens, I'll work hard enough to make up for their part.
I'll hold you to that, Daikuhara.
Keep quiet, Sawamura.
If they attack under these conditions, only we can protect the Yamato.
But aren't we leaving the missus?
Yeah, she's our ace in the hole.
Don't trust aliens. If you do, we'll all die... We'll all die!
Breaking through turbulence layer!
Seas are calm out here.
Something on radar!
Enemy fighter formation. Twenty-seven light seconds away.
Battle stations!
All crew to battle stations. Fighter Group, launch immediately!
They're coming... And bringing the war with them.
One hundred. Kato... Launching!
All fighters have launched!
Episode 19
They're Coming!
Among the distant stars
Can you hear the wandering souls?
In this galaxy, they can forever rest in peace
Requiem of separation
With this requiem
Sing Along!
Voices sing to praise
An unforgettable memory
And we’ll never forget your name
Farewell friend,
my sorrow
Will not run out
Someday in this sea of stars
Surely
Pray for the Earth!
The oath
Pray for the dream!
The ideal
Last forever!
A pack of wolves descend. An invisible hunting dog
lurks in the shadows, ready to strike.
The battle begins in a rainbow sky.
The time has come to decide the final victor.
This battle is a test that must be passed.
Next time: Under a Rainbow Sun.
There are 245 days left before humanity is extinct.